Guide to the American Studies Program, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1939-1989; Accession 1990-A-025
  - The Social History of American Ethnicity: Italo-Americans in Comparative Perspective: Spring - Silliman, Calhoun Colleges, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 428)
  - Supreme Court in the Last Decade: Spring Seminar - Ezra Stiles. James P. Simon, Visiting Lecturer., 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 429)
  - Course Schedules - Graduate Students, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 430)
  - A.S. 191a: Mr. Susman, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 431)
  - A.S. 191b: Mr. Erikson, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 432)
  - A.S. 192a: Mr. Trachtenberg, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 433)
  - A.S. 192b: Mr. Susman, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 434)
  - A.S. 193b (History 190b): Mr. Howe, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 435)
  - A.S. 194: Directed Reading, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 436)
  - A.S. 195a: Independent Research, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 437)
  - A.S. 198b (A.S. 63b): Miss Marshall, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 438)
  - Religious Studies 202a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 439)
  - English 154: Mr. Bloom, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 440)
  - English 157b: Mr. McIntosh, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 441)
  - English 165a: Mr. Pearson, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 442)
  - History 188a: Mr. Blum, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 443)
  - History of Art 393a: Mr. Wilmerding - Fall, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 444)
  - Religious Studies 202b: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 445)
  - Westerns of John Ford Series, 1972-73 (Box 8, Folder 446)
  - A.S. 32a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 447)
  - A.S. 32b: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 448)
  - A.S. 55a: Mr. Ferris, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 449)
  - A.S. 56a: Mr. McIntosh, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 450)
  - A.S. 59a: Mr. Davis, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 451)
  - A.S. 70: Mr. Lesy, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 452)
  - A.S. 71b: Mr. Lesy, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 453)
  - A.S. 82b, 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 454)
  - A.S. 83b: Mr. Rice, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 455)
  - History 84a: Mr. Davis, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 456)
  - A.S. 91-1, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 457)
  - A.S. 91-2, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 458)
  - A.S. 91-4, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 459)
  - A.S. 91-5, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 460)
  - A.S. 92-1, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 461)
  - A.S. 92-3b: Mr. Ferris, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 462)
  - A.S. 92-5: Mr. Metcalf, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 463)
  - A.S. 92-6: Ms. Perlis, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 464)
  - A.S. 92-7: Mr. Warch, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 465)
  - A.S. 92-8b: Mr. Roemer, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 466)
  - A.S. 93a: Mr. McIntosh, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 467)
  - History 22a: Mr. Warch, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 468)
  - Graduate Registration Forms, Course Schedules, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 469)
  - A.S. 191a: Mr. Davis, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 470)
  - A.S. 192b: Mr. Ferris, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 471)
  - A.S. 194: Directed Reading, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 474)
  - A.S. 196a: Warch/Williams, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 475)
  - A.S. 197b: Lamar/Musto, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 476)
  - A.S. 198a: Mr. Ferris, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 477)
  - A.S. 199a: Mr. Rice, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 478)
  - History 183b: Mr. D. Davis, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 479)
  - History of Art 251b: Mr. Montgomery, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 480)
  - Religious Studies 203a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 481)
  - Independent Reading and Research, 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 482)
  - A.S. 10a: Mr. Erikson, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 483)
  - A.S. 32a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 484)
  - A.S. 33b: Mr. Caskey, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 485)
  - A.S. 56a: Mr. McIntosh, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 487)
  - A.S. 56b: Mr. Lewis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 488)
  - A.S. 58b: Forrey, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 489)
  - A.S. 59a: Mr. C. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 490)
  - A.S. 59b: Ms. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 491)
  - A.S. 66b: Ms. Forrey, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 493)
  - A.S. 72b: Ms. Perlis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 494)
  - A.S. 84a: Mr. D. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 495)
  - A.S. 84b: Mr. D. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 496)
  - A.S. 86a: Mr. Rustin, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 497)
  - A.S. 91-1: Ms. Caskey, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 498)
  - A.S. 91-2: Mr. Stannard, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 499)
  - A.S. 92-1: Mr. Trachtenberg, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 500)
  - A.S. 91-4: Mr. Bynack, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 501)
  - A.S. 92-2: Mr. Pearson, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 502)
  - A.S. 91-3: Ms. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 503)
  - A.S. 92-3: Mr. Brandstein, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 504)
  - A.S. 92-5: Mr. Metcalf, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 505)
  - A.S. 92-6a: Ms. Perlis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 506)
  - A.S. 92-8: Mr. Roemer, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 507)
  - A.S. 92-10: Ms. Caskey, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 508)
  - A.S. 92-11: Mr. Stannard, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 509)
  - A.S. 92-12b: Mr. Stannard, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 510)
  - A.S. 93, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 511)
  - History 191a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 515)
  - History 203b: Mr. Lamar, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 516)
  - History 208b: Mr. da Costa & Mr. Wilson, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 517)
  - History 210b: Mr. Williams, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 518)
  - History 298b: Directed Reading, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 519)
  - Sociology 131b: Mr. Erikson, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 520)
  - Religious Studies 203a: Mr. Ahlstrom, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 521)
  - Course Schedules, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 522)
  - A.S. 190b: Mr. Franklin, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 523)
  - A.S. 191a: Mr. D. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 524)
  - A.S. 192a: Mr. Trachtenberg, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 525)
  - A.S. 194, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 526)
  - History 194a: Mr. Harris, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 528)
  - A.S. 195, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 529)
  - A.S. 198a: Mr. Brandstein, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 530)
  - A.S. 199b: Ms. Carden, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 531)
  - English 154b: Mr. Trachtenberg, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 532)
  - English 166a: Mr. Lewis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 533)
  - History 182: Mr. D. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 534)
  - History 184b: Mr. D. Davis, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 535)
  - History 188b: Mr. Blum, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 536)
  - History 189a: Mr. Blum, 1974-75 (Box 9, Folder 537)
  - French Language Exam, 1962-1967, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 538 - 543)
  - Language Exams, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 544)
  - Language Exams: French, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 545)
  - German Translation Examinations, undated (Box 9, Folder 546)
  - German Language Exam, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 547 - 555)
  - Language Examinations prior to 1960, 1954-60 (Box 9, Folder 556)
  - Language Examinations Sept., 1960 --, undated (Box 9, Folder 557)
  - Other Language Exams, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 558)
  - Speakers' Programs, 1974-76 (Box 9, Folder 559)
  - Graduate Catalogue, 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 560 - 561)
  - College Seminars, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 562 - 563)
  - Summer Program in A.S., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 564)
  - Summer Programs in A.S., 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 565 - 566)
  - Summer Program in A.S., 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 569 - 575)
  - Summer Program Inquiries, 1965-72 (Box 10, Folder 576)
  - Summer Program Reading Lists, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 578)
  - Summer Program in A.S.: Expenses, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 581)
  - Summer Program in A.S.: Subjects, 1958-66 (Box 10, Folder 582)
  - Summer Session: June 27 to Aug. 5, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 583)
  - Summer Term, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 584)
  - Summer program in A.S.: Alumni Directory, 1956-66 (Box 10, Folder 585)
  - Summer Term, Committee on Teaching, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 586)
  - Summer Term: A.S. Students -- Supplementary Enrollment Schedules of Courses, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 587)
  - Comprehensive Examinations for A.S. Majors, 1950-68 (Box 10, Folder 588)
  - Departmental Examinations, 1957-68 (Box 10, Folder 589)
  - Reports on Senior Essays, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-60 (Box 10, Folder 591)
  - A.S. Honors Majors, 1949-50 (Box 10, Folder 592)
  - A.S. Intensive Majors, 1950-1958 (Box 10, Folder 593 - 599)
  - Procedures: Standard Program, 1958-65 (Box 10, Folder 600)
  - A.S. Intensive Majors, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 601 - 602)
  - Procedures: Honors Program, 1960-66 (Box 10, Folder 603)
  - A.S. Standard Major, 1960-61 (Box 10, Folder 604)
  - A.S. Honors Majors, 1960-61 (Box 10, Folder 605)
  - A.S. Intensive Majors, 1961-62 (Box 10, Folder 606)
  - A.S. Standard Majors, 1961-62 (Box 10, Folder 607)
  - A.S. Honors Majors, 1962-63 (Box 10, Folder 608)
  - Standard Program, 1962-63 (Box 11, Folder 609)
  - A.S. Intensive Majors, 1963-64 (Box 11, Folder 610)
  - A.S. Standard Majors, 1963-64 (Box 11, Folder 611)
  - Readings for the Honors Program, 1964-67 (Box 11, Folder 612)
  - Honors Majors, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 613)
  - Standard Majors, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 614)
  - A.S. Intensive Majors, 1965-66 (Box 11, Folder 615)
  - Standard Majors, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 616)
  - A.S. Standard Major, 1966-67 (Box 11, Folder 617)
  - Honors and Departmental Honors: Standard Majors, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 618)
  - Intensive Majors: Readers, 1967-68 (Box 11, Folder 619)
  - A.S. 92 Applicants, 1967-68 (Box 11, Folder 620)
  - Notes regarding Intensive, 1968-72 (Box 11, Folder 622)
  - Intensive Readers, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 623)
  - A.S. Majors: Forms and Form Letters, 1970-71 (Box 11, Folder 625)
  - Readers' Reports: Senior Essays, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 626)
  - Intensives: Harry Henderson, Director, 1970-71 (Box 11, Folder 627)
  - A.S. 86 Intensive Majors -- Readers' reports, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 628)
  - Undergraduate Honors and Prizes, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 629)
  - A.S. 86 Intensive Reports, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 630)
  - Intensive Major Applications, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 631)
  - A.S. 86: Intensive Major, Mrs. Caskey, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 632)
  - A.S. 86 Prospectuses, 1972-73 (Box 11, Folder 633)
  - Senior Intensive Essays, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 634)
  - Senior Essays, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 635 - 636)
  - A.S. 99: Readers' Reports, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 637)
- Records, 1976-1987; Accession 1990-A-105
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2061
  - Employment
  - Dossier Request, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Student Resume Info, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Readers Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Social History Search (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Affirmative Action Cards, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Approvals, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Social History Search Candidates, 1983-1984
  - References (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Rejections A - L (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Rejections M - Z (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Twentieth Century History Position, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Applications for Assistant Professor of English and American Studies, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Job Search, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Affirmative Action Cards, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Twentieth Century History Position Candidates, 1986-1987
  - Junior Search Committee, 1987
  - A - B (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - C (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - D - F (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - G - H (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - I - K (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - L (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - M (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - N - R (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - S (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - T - Z (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Liaison Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Newsletter, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Material for Newsletter: Drafts of Spring Copy, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Spring, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Program Schedule and Outline, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Senior Essays
  - Reader's Report on American Studies Senior Essays, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 332-334)
  - Completed 692 Forms, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 335)
- Student and faculty records, circa 1941-1989; Accession 1990-A-158
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2064
  - Students
  - Faculty
- Student, faculty, and staff records, circa 1974-1989; Accession 1993-A-014
  - Visting fellows, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Graduate Student Evaluations
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Job Search, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Letters Written to Dean Lamar For Search, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Faculty Job Search Professorial, Full-Time, No Date (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Executive Committee
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Graduate Studies Committee
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Visiting Fellows, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Educational board games created by students to learn about 19th century American culture, circa 1990; Accession 2001-A-112 (Box 1)
- Report of the American Studies Curriculum Committee, circa 1975; Accession 2001-A-181
  - Report of the American Studies Curriculum Committee, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of the American Studies Curriculum Committee (copy), circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)